FIELD TRIP, DAY TWO
（校外教學第二天）
Okay.
好
Today you're free to go where you want. Have fun!
今天是自由活動，大家自己去玩吧！
Yes ma'am!
好！
Komi!
古見同學！
-When a person has extreme social anxiety. -AYAMI SASAKI, MIKUNI KATO
-所謂的“交流障礙症”… -（佐佐木彩美，加藤三九二）
They struggle to communicate with others.
是指不擅長和人交流的一種症狀 或是指有這種症狀的人
-Bear in mind. -GOOD MORNING.
-不過需要注意的是… -（早安）
They only struggle to form connections.
這些人只是不擅長社交
It doesn't mean they don't want to.
但並不表示他們不想和別人有往來
Well…
那麼…
-L-Let's go, then… -AWKWARD
-我們就出發吧 -（尷尬）
Uh… Yeah…
好，走吧
I hope they're okay.
她們不會有問題吧？
MISSION 69 "IT'S JUST THE 2ND DAY OF THE FIELD TRIP."
（任務69 是校外教學第二天）
S-So awkward…!
氣氛好尷尬！
I'm not surprised.
這也難怪
We were so nervous during the meeting, we couldn't plan anything.
之前分組討論時大家都太緊張 不敢發言，導致什麼行程都沒規劃
But it's alright, Komi!
不過妳不用擔心，古見同學！
I'll make sure you have the best field trip ever!
我會讓妳充分享受 這趟校外教學之旅！
Um, I came up with a schedule for today.
那個，其實我已經 事先規劃好今天的行程了
Really? Kato, you're amazing!
真的嗎？加藤同學，準備得好周到！
I-If you don't mind, do you want to use this?
若是妳們不嫌棄 要不要照這個行程走走看？
Yeah, great!
好啊，真不錯！
DOESN'T REALIZE THEY'RE WAITING
（沒意識到兩人正在 徵求自己的同意）
NOD
（點頭）
Yeah!
好耶！
Alright, first is Osaka.
那第一站先去大阪的
To Utopia Street Japan.
烏托邦環街影城
We're leaving Kyoto already?!
第一站就馬上離開京都？
Kato, what do you do in your free time?
加藤同學，妳平常假日 都在做些什麼呢？
Hm. I mostly play shogi.
這個嘛，我應該都在下將棋
Shogi?
將棋？
Yeah. My grandpa was a shogi master.
對呀，我爺爺曾是職業棋士
He teaches me.
我在跟他學習
You mean the famous…?
妳爺爺該不會是叫一二三吧？
How about you, Sasaki?
佐佐木同學，妳呢？
Who, me?
什麼？我嗎？
Oh, uh, you know.
我想想，我平時呢…
Nothing at all. Just sort of lazing around, you know?
我沒有特別做什麼 都在家裡無所事事
How about you, Komi? What do you do in your free time?
古見同學呢？妳假日都在做些什麼？
Nice pass, Sasaki!
問得好，佐佐木同學！
I LAZE AROUND TOO.
（我也都在家裡無所事事）
There it is!
出現了！
Typical beautiful girl who says, "I don't have a beauty routine."
美女最愛說“我平常都沒努力保養
"I just laze around at home."
我都在家無所事事”這類的話！
She's not opening up to us at all!
表示她完全不肯對我們敞開心胸！
UTOPIA STREET JAPAN
（烏托邦環街影城，USJ）
Wow, it's so crowded.
天啊，人山人海
It'll take a long time to get on the rides.
看來要排很久才能玩到遊樂設施
SLIDE
（拿出）
-Leave it to me. -EXTRA PASS TO GET ON RIDES QUICKLY
-包在我身上 -（快速通關券）
MR. SPIDER 3D RIDE
（3D《蜘蛛先生》）
-That was awesome. -IN TRANSIT
-好精彩喔 -（移動）
I think I'll chose the Honey one.
我選蜂蜜的好了
HONEY POTTER STORE
（哈尼波特店）
-Wait, Komi, that one? -Same as me.
-古見同學，妳要選那個嗎？ -跟我選的一樣
Then I'll get one too!
什麼？那我也要那個
-A-Aren't you walking kind of fast? -IN TRANSIT
-妳是不是走太快了？加藤同學 -（移動）
Watch out!
危險！
Wow, she hasn't budged.
好厲害，她完全不為所動
-TOO SCARED TO MOVE -SHARK THE RIDE
（古見同學嚇到全身僵硬 大白鯊驚魂）
Whew! That was so fun!
真過癮！好好玩喔！
What to ride next?
接下來要坐哪個？
Next is takoyaki.
接下來是章魚燒
-Huh? Ta… what? -RIDE IT?
-什麼？章魚… -（坐章魚燒？）
Y-You mean leave Utopi? It's still morning!
已經要離開烏托邦了嗎？ 還不到中午耶！
-We can stay for 40 seconds more. -GET READY.
-我們能待在這裡的時間剩40秒 -（快點準備）
40 seconds?!
40秒？
-Komi, are your legs okay? -IN TRANSIT
-古見同學，妳的腳還好吧？ -（移動）
Three packs of eight!
妳要三份八顆的對吧？
They're hot, so be careful!
很燙，要小心喔
Thank you!
謝謝老闆
-Cheers! -Here they are!
-謝謝惠顧！ -久等了
Wow, it looks so good! Authentic takoyaki.
天啊，看起來超好吃！
Let's walk and eat. It is street food after all.
我們邊移動邊吃吧，難得可以帶著走
Huh?
什麼？
I-Isn't that bad manners? Let's just eat it here.
邊走邊吃不雅觀啦，吃完再走吧
Yeah, you're right.
說得也是
Wow, it's really good!
這個好好吃喔！
C'mon, let's go.
好了，我們走吧
You're done already? They're still hot!
什麼？妳已經吃完了？還很燙耶！
HUFFING
（吐氣）
HER MOUTH IS SUPER HOT.
（嘴裡超燙）
So committed…
有必要拼成這樣嗎？
Wow!
天啊！
The Buddha is so big!
大佛好大！
-There really are deer! -DEER
-真的有鹿耶！ -（鹿）
-S-She's so well prepared! -DEER CRACKERS
-準備得真萬全！ -（鹿仙貝）
Here, have a cracker!
來，是仙貝喔！
They really do eat them!
牠們真的會吃耶
Yeah!
對呀！
STARTLE
（嚇到）
-STEP -STARTLE
（前進 驚嚇）
BITE
（咬）
So cute.
好可愛！
She was indeed cute.
她真的很可愛
W-We got distracted watching Komi!
看古見同學看得太入迷了！
The train for Kyoto will leave from platform four.
四號月台開往京都的列車即將發車
Go on, Komi. You sit.
古見同學，妳可以先去坐喔
Whew. I'm so tired.
天啊，累死我了
Why'd you make such a packed schedule?
真是的，妳幹嘛把行程排得那麼滿？
If you had eaten your takoyaki faster, we would've had more time.
如果妳章魚燒可以吃快一點 我們就能稍微再從容一些啊
Huh? What? My fault?
什麼？所以是我害的？
Oh. Sure.
是喔
What the hell? We could've spent the whole day at Utopi.
這算什麼嘛 明明可以只排烏托邦就好
She tried to do too much and now look.
還不是因為妳太貪心 硬要去那麼多地方才會這樣
My fault? What the hell?
怎麼會全變成我的錯？什麼嘛！
She doesn't even know how I feel…
妳根本不懂我的心情
It's not like Sasaki made a schedule.
佐佐木同學又沒有花時間想行程
Must be nice to be irresponsible.
可以不負責地說那種話
But what's with that tone?
但有必要用那種口氣嗎？
-I… -STARTLE
-我… -（驚嚇）
LOUDER THAN EXPECTED
（古見同學不小心講太大聲）
PEEK
（冒出）
SUB-MENU, SELECT, SEND
（下方功能，選項，傳送）
IT REALLY WAS FUN THOUGH?
（今天玩得很開心）
BEEP
（按到）
Oh, no, Komi.
不是在笑妳啦，古見同學
That just tickled my funny bone. Sorry.
只是莫名被戳到笑點，抱歉
But it really was fun.
對呀，今天其實玩得很開心
You went to all that trouble to make a schedule. I'm sorry.
妳特地幫我們規劃行程 我還這樣抱怨，對不起
No, I'm sorry.
別這樣說，我也要跟妳們道歉
Having fun is the most important thing. Sorry for rushing you.
大家玩得盡興才是最重要的 我卻一直催妳們，真的很抱歉
Kyoto. Kyoto.
京都站到了…
I thought we could go to Futomaki Movie Land next.
本來接下來還要去太卷電影村
But we're tired. Let's cancel.
但大家都累了，還是取消吧
It's going to close soon anyway.
而且營業時間也快結束了
LET'S RUN.
（我們用跑的吧）
Yeah.
好啊
-Hey, wait… -Alright! Lead the way!
-什麼？等等… -快點幫我們帶路吧！
I can run by myself!
我自己可以跑！
Hey, c'mon. Let's go!
快點走吧，出發囉！
FUTOMAKI MOVIE LAND
（太卷電影村）
Wow! Komi you look great!
天啊！古見同學 這身打扮好適合妳！
I'm so glad we came to Movie Land.
有來電影村真的太好了
-Oh, a geisha girl! -Wonderful!
-哇，是藝妓女孩！ -太美了！
I-It seems Komi has international appeal!
不愧是古見同學，跟國際接軌了！
Hey, Sasaki…
對吧？佐佐木同…
Hm? She's gone.
奇怪，她怎麼不在這裡？
-You there! -SHAKE… STARTLE
-喂，小姑娘！ -（顫抖…驚嚇）
I knew it.
果然是妳
Although you're disguised as a maiko, I know you're the princess!
雖然妳打扮成藝妓的模樣 但妳就是公主本人沒錯！
You can't fool me!
妳逃不過我的法眼的！
-C'mon boys, take the princess away! -Yes sir!
-小子們，把公主帶走！ -是！
Wow!
太酷了！
The famous interactive theater attraction!
這就是太卷電影村最著名的 把觀光客捲入的表演節目！
It's a collaboration with Komi!
而且竟然還是和古見同學一起演出！
I'm glad we came to Movie Land!
有來電影村真的太好了
The women's washrooms sure are busy in places like this.
這種地方的女廁果然會排超多人
What's that? Something's happening!
怎麼了？那邊好像出事了
Huh? Is that Komi?
等等，話說那不是古見同學嗎？
She's surrounded by dangerous guys!
她好像被奇怪的人纏上了！
Kato? Why's she crying?
加藤同學？她怎麼在哭？
Oh no. No, no, no!
這下不得了，不妙啊！
Police!
得去報警！
Oh my god!
我的天啊！
I have to save her!
總之現在得先去救古見同學才行！
Oh yeah. If I use this…
對了，只要用這個…
But it's…
可是用這個…
It's kind of embarrassing!
會有點難為情！
But Komi's…
可是古見同學她…
Brace yourself.
妳就認命吧
-Halt! -Hm?
-給我等等！ -什麼？
-Who goes there?! -Huh? The Shogun's here already…?
-是什麼人？ -奇怪，將軍今天怎麼那麼快就來…
W-Who?
這是誰啊？
A yo-yo?
溜溜球？
STARTLE
（驚嚇）
SWIFT
（快速轉動）
Loop the Loop!
迴旋快打！
Wow!
好讚！
SPIN
（快速旋轉）
Spear Hop!
鎗式彈射！
Oh yeah!
好耶！
-C'mon! -Grand Twister!
-來吧！ -巨型炫風！
Woo! Amazing!
天啊！太驚人了！
And…
以及…
Big Tower!
大高塔！
S-She's wild.
這傢伙不太妙啊
H-Hey guys, let's scram!
小子們，我們撤退！
Y-Yes, sir!
遵命！
CHEERING
（歡呼）
Um, Sasaki?
那個，佐佐木同學
F-Farewell!
後會有期！
WOOSH
（奔跑）
Mm. Isn't it good?
真棒，這茶真好喝
Oh, Komi!
啊，古見同學！
Is everything okay?
妳沒事吧？
I passed a strange masked person.
我剛剛跟一個戴著 奇怪面具的人擦肩而過
Oh, um.
嗯，沒事
A-A person with a yo-yo just rescued Komi.
剛才有個拿溜溜球的人 來幫忙解圍了，對吧？
Huh? Really?!
什麼？真的嗎？
Whew, I'm so tired.
天啊，累死我了
But I feel like we got the most out of our field trip.
但這趟校外教學玩得很盡興呢
Right, you two?
妳們兩個也這麼想吧？
STARE
（盯）
Sasaki, about the yo-yo thing.
佐佐木同學，我想問妳溜溜球的事
Huh? Yo… yo-yo?
什麼？溜溜球？
W-Whatever could you be talking about?
妳在說什麼？
Checkmate in nine.
九步內定勝負
Kato entered the mystery zone.
加藤同學奇妙的開關被打開了
Just now at Movie Land, the masked person who saved Komi
就是剛才在電影村裡 有個戴面具的人跑來解救古見同學
was using yo-yos.
她用溜溜球擊退敵人，有活躍的表現
O-Oh, is that right?
是喔，這樣啊？
It's unusual to see yo-yos these days.
不過現代還有人 在玩溜溜球啊？真罕見
And a hannya mask! What a strange person.
而且還戴般若面具，那個人好奇怪喔
Hm?
怪了
That person was wearing a hannya mask.
我剛剛有說那個人
Did I say that?
是戴般若面具嗎？
Oh, no, no. I told you!
不，我不是說過嗎？
I passed a strange masked person.
我跟一個戴奇怪面具的人擦肩而過
Oh, that's right.
對了，也是啦！
Ah, and this!
還有啊，妳看這個
The under-eighteen yo-yo world champions.
這是U18國際溜溜球大賽的優勝名單
Third place. Can you see it?
妳看得到第三名的名字嗎？
-Ayami Sasaki. That's your name, isn't it? -PAWN TO 1-C
-“佐佐木彩美”，是妳的名字吧？ -（1三步成）
-Well now. It's a very common name. -KING TO 1-C
-不曉得耶，這名字很常見啊！ -（同玉）
On the train, you didn't say what you do in your free time.
今天我們在電車上聊到 放假在幹嘛時妳也是吞吞吐吐的
-You practice yo-yoing right? -ROOK TO 1-D
-妳其實放假都在練溜溜球吧？ -（1四飛）
-No, I really just laze around. -KING TO 2-C
-怎麼可能，我真的都在家無所事事 -（2三玉）
Alright, open your bag.
那讓我看妳的包包
-There should be a mask. -KNIGHT TO 1-E
-裡面應該會有般若面具 -（1五桂）
-No! It's my private property! -KING TO 1-D
-不要，包包裡有裝少女的祕密！ -（1四玉）
ARE THEY FIGHTING?
（她們在吵架嗎？）
I'm working on becoming a professional shogi master.
其實我將來的目標是成為將棋棋士
The professional league is on a different level from the women's league.
妳知道女性棋士跟男性棋士 實力相差非常多嗎？
In shogi, there is a huge gap between the men and women.
在將棋的世界裡，男女實力天差地別
Four dan.
四段
How many women have joined the professional league?
目前當上職業棋士的女性人數…
Zero.
是零
But what does that mean?
但是那又怎樣？
Male? Female?
這跟是男是女
It doesn't mean a thing.
一點關係都沒有
I'll be a pro shogi player.
我想要成為一名棋士
Where my grandfather competed.
我要到我爺爺
I'll go there.
曾奮戰過的地方
I'm determined.
我的憧憬
I won't give up.
是永遠不會停止的
I'm trying to say,
所以說啊
When I see someone competing on a world-class level, I love it!
我只要看到有人能活躍於 世界最前線都會覺得很厲害
I think that's really cool!
覺得超帥的
It was you, wasn't it? Sasaki.
那個人就是妳吧？佐佐木同學
BISHOP TO 2-D CHECKMATE!
（2四馬，將死）
Wow.
是喔
-Oh, no, it's not me. -ANNOYED
-啊，但那個人不是我喔 -（火大）
I already know! Hurry up and confess! You have a yo-yo!
我知道那就是妳！ 快點從實招來，妳有帶溜溜球吧？
Aah! No! Stop! Harassment! I'm being groped!
討厭，不要過來 有色狼，她是色狼！
Give it!
把包包給我！
I WANT TO THANK HANNYA FOR RESCUING ME.
（我想向幫我解圍的 般若面具小姐道謝）
"Even if it was just a Movie Land attraction…"
“就算那是電影村的表演節目…”
"…the act of trying to rescue me made me happy."
“她來救我這件事仍讓我感到高興”
Huh? H-Huh? Hang on a second.
什麼？等一下
That was all an attraction?
那個是表演節目嗎？
Oh, now that you mention it, Sasaki seemed to misunderstand…
話說回來，她好像誤會了…
I'm going to use the bathroom.
我去一下洗手間
Augh! This is the worst!
天啊！怎麼會這樣？
I… I'm so embarrassed! I wish I could disappear!
太丟臉了吧，好想消失！
This'll be a trauma for life!
這會成為我一輩子的陰影！
So embarrassing.
好丟臉
Anyway,
所以說啊
what's a girl doing with yo-yos?
女生玩什麼溜溜球？
These days, yo-yos are uncool!
現在怎麼還有人在玩溜溜球，好遜！
-Let's play Bey over there. -Yeah.
-我們去那邊玩戰爆陀螺吧 -好
Let's go! Three, two, one!
要來囉，三、二、一！
Go, shoot!
發射！
I'm trying to say…
所以說啊
When I see someone competing on a world-class level, I love it!
我只要看到有人能活躍於 世界最前線都會覺得很厲害
I think that's really cool!
覺得超帥的
I WANT TO THANK HANNYA FOR RESCUING ME.
（我想向幫我解圍的 般若面具小姐道謝）
I'm not embarrassed anymore…
我現在已經不會覺得丟臉了…
I guess.
應該吧
Hey there! I'm Y. Y. Hannya!
嗨，妳們好，我是溜溜般若！
Enjoy my yo-yo performance today!
今天就盡情享受我的溜溜球表演吧！
BAM
（氣勢磅礴）
The future world-class yo-yo performer Y.Y. Hannya was born that day.
未來的世界級溜溜球表演大師 “溜溜般若”在這一瞬間誕生了
THAT WILL BE 4,500 YEN, PLEASE.
（總共4500圓）
But I never thought she would be right behind me.
不過我當時壓根沒想到 本人就在我身後
I was like, "Whew, I've said it now."
就想說“糟糕，不小心說出來了”
Ah, that happens.
我懂，這種事常發生
Oh, it's about time for lights out.
差不多該關燈了
Well now.
那麼接下來
Shall we begin?
就開始吧
Girl talk!
來聊戀愛話題！
Well, Sasaki? Do you have a boyfriend?
佐佐木同學，妳有男朋友嗎？
Ooh, so aggressive!
天啊，妳問得真直接
Sorry, but I have no fun gossip for you.
很遺憾，這方面我沒什麼話題可以聊
How about you, Kato? Any crushes?
加藤同學，妳有喜歡的人嗎？
I don't have a crush either.
我也沒有喜歡的人
Hm? That's not the vibe I'm getting.
等等，這什麼令人在意的回答？
You're curious about someone?
所以妳是有“在意的人”嗎？
C'mon now, out with it!
說來聽聽嘛！
K-Katai.
是片居同學
Really? Isn't he scary?
真的假的？他不會很可怕嗎？
T-That's not it! I'm just curious about him.
沒有啦，我只是有一點在意他而已！
It's not a crush or anything!
沒有喜歡他啦！
What do you like about him?
妳喜歡他哪一點？
H-His eyes are so intense…
他的眼神看起來很銳利…
But it's not a crush!
就說了不是喜歡嘛！
I don't need all this attention!
討厭啦，都一直問我，不公平！
How about Komi?
古見同學呢？
We ask, but we already know it's Tadano.
但不用問也知道 是只野同學吧？我們知道啦
You're always together. It would be weird if you didn't.
你們那麼常在一起，不是才奇怪
WHAT, SPECIFICALLY, DOES A CRUSH FEEL LIKE?
（所謂的喜歡 具體來說是什麼樣的感覺呢？）
For real?
真的假的？
Tadano, come in Tadano.
聯絡只野同學…
She hasn't noticed how a crush feels.
目前的狀況就是女方 完全沒察覺到自己喜歡的心情
This is trouble! Over!
這可難辦囉，完畢！
-Tadano, Komi's super-duper cute. Over! -ONE-WAY TELEPATHY SENT TO TADANO.
-只野同學，古見同學超可愛，完畢 -（被單方面傳送心電感應的只野）
Yeah, I mean, you feel relaxed together,
這個嘛，就是在一起的時候會很安心
but sometimes you feel excited.
但又會不時心動不已
And you suddenly think of that person…
回過神來就會 滿腦子都是那個人的事…
Stuff like that, right?
這應該就叫喜歡吧
So cute!
好可愛！
-You do have one! What's his name? -CUTE…
-看來是有喜歡的人！說他的名字！ -（好可愛）
Who? Who is it?
誰？到底是誰？
Alright, just the first letter. Give us the first letter!
不然講名字第一個音就好 羅馬拼音的第一個音！
Not his family name, his given name. Okay?
不用講姓氏，講名字就行，好不好？
RELIEF
（鬆一口氣）
It's H.
是“H”啊
It was H.
就是H
LAST DAY OF THE TRIP
（校外教學 最後一天）
The train is leaving!
新幹線要開了！
Run!
快跑啊！
You fool!
妳這笨蛋！
M-My Chrysanthemum Blade of Darkness!
我的暗黑菊一文字！
They came right up to you!
結果就跑到很前面來！
Was that…
那個是…
She fell asleep.
她好像睡著了
She didn't get much sleep for the past two nights.
她昨天和前天好像都沒怎麼睡
What's up?
怎麼了？
-A NEW DISCOVERY. -Komi sleeps too!
-（新發現） -我在想原來古見同學也會睡覺啊
What did you think Komi is?
妳到底把古見同學當成什麼了？
How can I put it?
該怎麼說呢？
I thought Komi was a perfect superwoman.
我一直以為古見同學是完美的超人
-Someone who never reveals a weakness. -Yeah.
-完全不會露出破綻 -是沒錯
But we spent a whole day together during the field trip.
但這次校外教學跟她相處一整天後
And she's pretty cute!
突然覺得她好像滿可愛的！
It's like she's surprisingly approachable.
而且其實很好親近
The Komi I had imagined,
跟我想像中的古見同學
was very different.
形象完全不一樣
You're scheming.
妳的表情看起來好壞
It was weirdly fun, wasn't it.
那個不知道為什麼還滿興奮的
-Tadano, Tadano! -Hm?
-只野同學！ -怎麼了？
Komi's being harassed over there!
古見同學在那邊被壞人襲擊了！
Go rescue her!
快點去救她！
-HIGH-FIVE -STARTLE
（擊掌！ 驚嚇）
And now our plan to get Komi and Tadano alone is mostly complete.
這下讓只野同學和古見同學 獨處的作戰大致上就成功了
Now to fill in the seat where Tadano was sitting.
再來只要找人坐 只野同學原來的位子…
Huh?
什麼？
You told me your crush.
妳都跟我說了妳在意的人了
You thought I wouldn't act on that information?
妳以為我會少管這個閒事嗎？
Bamboozled!
被算計了！
Uh, are you alright? Komi…
那個，妳沒事吧？古見同學
Huh? She's sleeping.
奇怪？她在睡覺
RUMBLE
（隆隆聲）
Sit next to her.
在她旁邊坐下
Um… I guess I'll sit and wait.
好吧，那我就先坐下來等吧
P-Pardon me…
打擾了
This is my first time seeing Komi sleeping.
對了，我好像是第一次看到 古見同學睡著的模樣
No, no, no!
不行！
Don't watch someone sleep!
我怎麼可以一直盯著人家的睡臉看！
That's rude!
太沒禮貌了！
Oh, did you wake up?
啊，妳醒了嗎？
HE TRIED TO PLAY IT COOL BUT HIS PULSE RACED. HIS BOOK WAS UPSIDE DOWN.
（只野同學想用撲克臉裝沒事 但他想用來掩飾害羞的書拿反了）
-WARMTH FROM HER HEAD -Komi?
-（頭靠過的餘溫） -古見同學？
-HOW LONG WERE YOU THERE? -Only two or three minutes.
-（我什麼時候開始靠著你的？） -只有兩、三分鐘而已啦
I'M SORRY.
（不好意思）
-No, not at all. -KOMI CHECKING FOR DROOL.
-不，不用在意 -（古見同學在確認是否有流口水）
Where did you go during free time?
對了，妳們自由時間去了哪裡玩？
-WE WENT TO OSAKA, NARA, AND FUTOMAKI. -Wow, you moved around a lot.
-（大阪、奈良、太卷電影村） -天啊，跑了好多地方喔
-WANT TO SEE SOME PHOTOS? -Oh, yes please.
-（要看照片嗎？） -好啊，我想看
I-It's so out of focus…
這張照片明顯失焦了呢…
So much happened!
原來妳們那邊發生了很多事啊！
Did you have fun?
玩得還開心嗎？
-That's-- -What's up?
-太好了… -你們在看什麼？
Hey, the seat's free. Lucky!
這裡有空位耶，好幸運！
I'll sit here.
我要坐這裡
-Hey, be careful… -Oh no, my leg! I got a cramp! Ow ow ow!
-等一下，你這樣很危險 -糟糕，我的腳抽筋了，好痛！
-Just kidding! -Huh? Why would you lie?
-騙你的啦！ -什麼？你幹嘛撒謊啊？
I was kidding that I was kidding. Help me up.
我在開玩笑，拉我起來
"At the inn on the first night,
“第一天晚上我在旅館看到
you were taking pictures of half-naked boys.
你在拍男生們光著上半身的照片
What for?"
那是在做什麼呢？”
Huh?
什麼？
What? Show me!
什麼啊？我也要看！
-Oh, no, that was… -Why!
-沒有，那個是… -幹嘛不給我看？
-That was, uh… -Show us! Show us!
-沒有，那個只是… -我要看，給我看！
-Uh, um. -Show us now!
-就是那個… -給我看！
BONUS SCENE
（片尾彩蛋）
TADANO AND NAJIMI RETURNED TO THEIR SEATS
（只野同學和馴染回座位後）
REMEMBERING HOW SHE SLEPT ON TADANO'S SHOULDER (EMBARRASSED)
（古見同學想起自己靠在只野同學 肩膀上睡覺，覺得害羞）
Did you have a good trip?
這趟旅程還開心嗎？
Hey, Sasaki. Why did you get me involved?!
佐佐木同學，妳不要連我一起陷害！
79 more to go.
距離交100個朋友…
-It was super embarrassing! -Until 100 friends.
-害我超害羞的！ -還剩79人
Subtitle translation by: Claire Tanaka
字幕翻譯：林琬清